in this video i'm going to show you how
to build a robot to edit for you
no i'm not i'm actually not going to
show you how to do that maybe one day
but i am going to share with you five
tips to speed up your editing workflow
so that you can save time because
who's got time for editing nobody's got
time for that without further ado let's
jump right into this video here we go
you got to just press record
quick warning for you guys out there i
am going to be using final cut pro 10
in this video but these tips are going
to work with any editing software so you
definitely want to stay tuned
but if you're using final cut pro 10
then you are superior than everyone else
i'm sorry omar all right let's get into
it tip number one is to use
proxies nolan what is a proxy
good question a proxy is a lower quality
version of your actual video so you can
edit with this lower quality version
your computer runs a whole lot faster
you're not going to run into
drop frame rates or loading times
anything like that because
it's it's lower quality and then at the
very end of editing you switch out the
lower quality with your good quality and
it does all the magic
and it replaces all those files and then
when you export it it looks beautiful
it looks high quality and it's gorgeous
and you save time because you're editing
with the lower quality stuff making your
computer run faster
this is how you do it inside of final
cut pro x you can see right here i have
my library set up i got my event
and project ready to go i'm solid all i
need to do is import some footage
i'm gonna right click i'm gonna hit
import media and at this point let me go
to the correct
folder right here in my hide likes and
comments folder is an upcoming video i'm
going to edit for think media
to the right you are going to see this
transcode
section this is where you can actually
create the proxies
and i'll show you how this is stored and
all that kind of good stuff but
there are basically two different things
you need to know here you got optimized
media and you have proxy media
optimized media basically says that it's
going to take your sony or canon files
whatever you're shooting with it's going
to turn it into a
progress file and that is going to run
smoother inside of final cut pro 10. now
a lot of you guys probably already had
that turned on but your files are still
running so
because it's 4k and you know your
computer probably is not that good
well proxy is going to be better for you
if your computer is older
or if your videos are running slow in
your editing software now under our
proxy media we have prores proxy and we
have h.264
honestly you could use either of these
i've tried both of them out and they
both run
great on my computer but i like to use
prores proxies because final cut pro
likes to use pro res because it's apple
and anyways
doesn't matter but i like to use prores
proxy and here you can choose a frame
size now i shoot all my stuff
in 4k 50 is gonna turn that in to 1080
hd
and it actually doesn't even look too
bad i mean of course it is lower quality
but it honestly really doesn't look that
bad i definitely recommend trying that
out and seeing how your computer runs
now if it's still running a little bit
slow
you can set it to a lower resolution
like 25
or 12.5 percent 25 for me i've used it
before and it definitely
works great 50 works for me too but 25
is a lower quality and it's just going
to give you faster
files to work with when editing down
here you could also set it to you know
1080 hd which is the same as 50
but you have those options down here for
me i'm just going to leave mine at 50
percent
you don't need to have optimized media
selected because we are going to be
using proxies the whole time so from
here all you have to do is hit import
selected
and because i have the folder selected
that is going to make proxy files
for everything in the folder nice and
easy i'm going to hit
import selected boom so we are importing
and you're going to see something right
up here if you click on this circle
you are going to get this window and
this is going to tell you
what is happening and it tells you that
it's transcoding and analysis
remember we are transcoding some of our
footage right now
so if i bring this down you can see
there's three clips that it is
turning into proxy files so we're gonna
give this a few minutes we're gonna take
a sip of water
and uh come back to it when it's ready
to go
[Music]
am i the only one who uses a gigantic
water bottle
99 100. okay sweet so we're all done
and we can exit out of this our proxy
files are now made
before i show you how to actually use
these in final cut pro x let me show you
where they are stored
so inside the folder where i actually
uploaded all that footage it was two
video files and one audio file we have
an optimized media and proxy media now
this kind of confuses me because i
didn't select
optimize media but in here we have the
it looks like it is the audio but for
some reason it's a
mov but it's the audio file anyway so
there's that but then in our proxy which
is what we're going to be using
we have our video files i
couldn't get that word out so right here
if i open this up we can see that it
doesn't even look that bad honestly but
this
is our proxy file and then we have our
screen share
and you can see this definitely does
look a bit lower quality than what it
actually was
okay this is how you use them now in
final cut pro 10 for people wondering
where they're stored
that is exactly where they're stored
nice and easy okay moving on so let's go
ahead and just throw my entire video
down
into this timeline so i can show you
guys how to use this so we got our video
right here and basically all you need to
do is go to this upper right hand corner
where it says view
and change this from optimized original
to proxy now proxy only or proxy
preferred here's the difference proxy
only
will only show you proxies so if you
have something in there that was not
proxied if i
add in a new video that maybe i didn't
make into a proxy file it's not going to
show that's why i like to use proxy
preferred because then it can mix in the
two
and it's using proxies if it has it so
i'm just going to select proxy preferred
and now this video in my timeline is the
proxy
now before going out to actually share
and export the video
you want to make sure you change this
back to optimized original
it's okay if you forget because uh final
cut pro actually let you know
we'll say hey do you want to export your
proxies and you're going to say no
and then you're going to go back you're
going to change it and then re-export it
so
don't worry about that but that's how
you do it and that is going to speed up
your workflow a ton
especially if you have an older laptop
an older computer
definitely start using proxies i hate
the the spinning wheel of death
the drop frames all that stuff it slows
it down we're trying to save time
number two i'm gonna call speedy rough
cut okay we are going to
speed through and fly through this uh 11
minute and 24
second clip and trim it down by this
little editing
workflow thing that i do let me show you
so i filmed the video in one
long clip and i need to trim it down
into all the good parts
and i'm going to show you exactly how i
do this for every single video and i
swear it saves me so much time
now if you are going through and you're
starting at the beginning and you're
just hitting play
and you're watching this like this is
boring you don't want to watch this
we can skip through all of this and save
a bunch of time the main thing that you
want to look for here
is the audio waveforms we are going to
be editing
while looking at the audio waveforms and
that is
these little waveforms down here we are
going to be using these
right here you can see there are no
waveforms which means it's silent which
means i'm not talking
and therefore we can go ahead and just
cut that out to start with okay
so that's that that's kind of the idea
but we're gonna get deeper and i'm gonna
show you how you can really start to
save time
by using these waveforms now because i
shot this video i already know
that this beginning part really is
nothing because i kind of mess with the
background and then i come back over and
i start
right around this point so i'm going to
go ahead and just chop all this off
and i'm going to show you how to do this
right now so officially
right here is when i start the video and
i start trying to talk to it now instead
of hitting play and listening to my
entire take
what i do is i hit play i listen to the
first like
three four five words and then i move to
the next
audio waveform and then i move to the
next one and the next one
because what happens when i shoot videos
like this is i often mess up
and then i'll redo what i was trying to
say and when i move on to my next
sentence i know that my last take
was my best take and so that's how i get
my rough cut let me actually just show
you exactly how i do this
now in order to disable now in order to
turn off
now in order to turn off your in order
to hide your
now in order to hide your dislikes and
your likes and
to hide your dislikes and you're like
what i like to do
okay i moved on because what i was
saying is in order to disable in order
to turn off whatever right
right here it was uh the last time that
i said that when i
jumped forward to this next waveform i
was talking about something different
so i know for sure that this is at least
probably my last take i know that this
was the same thing but i'm gonna go
ahead and delete
all of that and now i'm going to listen
to this again
it looks like there might be some pauses
right in this area maybe in this area
i can't tell if i just talked slower
there or if that's an actual pause
but i'm going to go ahead and listen to
that right now now in order to hide your
dis
videos first thing one you want to make
sure
once you have done studio okay so i know
that's all good because i kept talking i
never stopped and so i'm going to go
ahead and hit
b on my keyboard and select right there
because i know that's the end of the
clip
and i'm going to do the same thing again
so you can see here that i'm really
trying to figure out what i want to say
this is probably the hook in the video
and so i'm going to fast forward because
look all of this is just nothing i'm
kind of probably writing something out
i'm thinking about what i'm going to say
i'm going to do it again right here all
right here we go
now i'm going to show you now i'm going
to show you right now i'm going to show
you how to do this on a video
you can also do this all right so this
right here this is it i'm going to
delete all of this
and keep going i'm going to show you how
this when you are uploading
this that way you never every time you
can just do
let's say you want to and you can also
you can all you can also do this on
mult now if you wanted to do this
on all your videos you also do this on
multiple videos
so i'm actually saying the same thing
here so i know that i redid it i just
changed the wording a little bit
and also here's another thing i can see
that i talked for a long time right here
which makes me think that this is
probably my best take
so i'm going to go ahead and delete that
because i already know that i redid it
and but let me hear it because i might
have redone it i don't remember but
that's why you just listened to the
first little bit you don't have to
listen to all of it
you can do that in the next step so
that's basically how i go through
the first cut on every single think
media video i look at the waveforms i
listen to the first couple words and
then i figure out which was my last take
which was my best take and i move on
from there so now that i have a rough
cut in order to just go ahead and watch
it
through maybe i want to cut some pieces
out instead of playing it back
at 100 and just watching it at 100
what i'm gonna do is i'm hit the space
bar and then i'm going to hit the letter
l now this is going to work on any
editing software and this is going to
speed up your playback so that you can
listen and watch it
at a faster time than a hundred percent
which is awesome because
you don't need to watch the whole thing
back at 100 especially when it's just a
rough cut and you're editing it
uh to trim down the fat and all that
kind of stuff so i'm going to hit the
space button then i'm going to hit l to
speed it up
now in order to hide your disc on
youtube as well as comments
on your videos first you want to do is
log into your youtube account now i use
this all the time sometimes i have 20
minute long tutorials on here that i'm
watching back
and just by hitting that l button to
watch it back i'm saving myself like
five minutes
okay every time i watch it all the way
through and that really adds up over
time as you are editing
your project inside your editing
software tip number four
is to copy and paste attributes most of
us know that you can hit command c
and then command v to copy and paste a
clip to another clip but what happens is
that
this pastes everything onto the next
clip that includes any audio effects
any cropping any sort of luts that you
put on
is going to paste everything well in
order just to copy and paste
a few things that you want to move on
whether it's just some audio effects or
maybe a color grade or maybe
a crop you can do that all you need to
do is select your clip we are going to
hit command
c and there are a few things different
uh on this clip than the rest of the
clips but let's say i want to paste that
the color grade only i don't want to
paste the crop you can see i have a crop
here
crops back out i just want to paste the
color grade what you want to do is hit
shift command
v and this is going to pull up your
paste attributes now this is really cool
because
you can select and deselect things that
you do not want to paste over
so like i said i do not want my crop so
i'm going to go ahead and just
unselect that and i changed the volume i
do not want to adjust the volume on this
next clip and now all i'm pasting over
is this custom lut so i'll hit paste and
you can see it has not affected
the audio it has not affected the crop
it's just sent over
my lut i use this all the time
especially for audio because usually i
have a grade done and then i'll do my
audio editing last
and i copy just the audio maybe the
volume and some eq and stuff like that
i'll copy it and paste it to all the
clips and it's not going to affect any
of my crop ins crop outs
or handheld shakes or anything that i do
like that it's only going to
paste over my audio effects same with
luts and different effects like that if
you are adding on
effects whether it be a crop or a lut
onto every single clip that you want
that's gonna be a waste of time select
all of them and just do paste attributes
select what you want it to be
it saved me a whole lot of time so now
you know tip number five
is to create presets this saves you so
much time because instead of eq'ing the
same mic
over and over again you can actually
create say an eq
like this for this usb mic and then i
can use that
every single time i use this mic it's a
preset it's built out i can click one
button and it's gonna do the rest for me
this works with video effects this works
with color grading you can actually save
a lot maybe with some tweaks that you've
made to it and then save this as a
preset that way when you add in the lut
it's also going to add in those little
tweaks that you've made to kind of make
it your own and fit your camera best
here's how you do it first let's start
with an audio preset so you can see here
that i've made
some adjustments to the eq on this
microphone
i can exit out of this you can see that
is the only thing i've done here
let's say i want the db to be zero okay
perfect
now to save this as a preset all you
have to do is go down here hit save
effects preset from here you can select
what you want to save so i'm just going
to call this
samsung q2u because that is the
microphone that i am using
you're also gonna see other options if
you add in some sort of like reverb or
noise reduction you're gonna have those
options here you can select them
but for me all i've done is some eq and
volume which is fine
and i and you definitely want to make
sure that stretch to fit is selected
that way
it takes whatever clip and it stretches
it out to the full thing
so that your effect is saved to your
entire clip
from here all you got to do is hit save
now what you can do is go over to your
effects you can scroll down to
audio and you can see that you have
custom and here are some of my
custom ones so i'm going to use the
samsung qtu that i
just made i'm going to drag it over this
clip right here
now you can see that it has added in my
eq
to be exactly like the other one this is
great if you use the same mic for your
youtube videos
you definitely want to be saving presets
because instead of eq'ing the same
mic in the same room every time you
don't need to do that just create a
preset and drag and drop and you're
gonna be set to go you can do the same
thing with video so you can see i have a
lut here and then i have some color
wheels where i just change some like
contrast stuff like that
but if i want to save this as a preset
both of these together i can go to save
effects preset now here i do want my
custom lot my color wheels but i do not
want my crop
and stretch to fit is fine i can go
ahead and rename this to
the a7s3 which is the camera that i'm
using for this shot
now something here and this is the same
with audio but the audio one was correct
here it's set to the category 360. i
actually don't want to save it to 360.
i'll save it to a new category
and we can call it custom you can really
call it whatever you want but i'll just
go ahead
and call it custom as well you'll hit
create and from there it's going to save
to a brand new category
called custom so now over here in the
effects if we go to custom you are going
to see my a7
s3 preset we can scroll over something
that has
no color on it and boom drag and drop
and you're good to go click or tap on
the screen for editing tips for making
better
youtube videos i will see you guys in
the next video